Guide to the Harry Clay Edwards Papers MC.401
New York University Archives
Harry Clay Edwards Papers
1888-circa 1930s
New York University Archives
Edwards, Harry Clay
MC.401
0.23 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box and 3 folders in a shared oversized flat box
Harry Clay Edwards was an illustrator in the late 1800s. The Harry Clay Edwards Papers (1888-circa 1930s) contains sketches and illustrations either done by Edwards or collected by him. The sketches depict a variety of themes such as men and women; children; costumes; and NYU's Washington Square and University Heights campuses. There are also engraving proofs and some correspondence from acquaintances.
Scope and Contents
The Harry Clay Edwards Papers (1888-circa 1930s) contains sketches and illustrations either done by Edwards or collected by him. The sketches depict a variety of themes such as men and women; children; costumes; and NYU's Washington Square and University Heights campuses. There are also engraving proofs and some correspondence from acquaintances.
Biographical Note
Harry Clay Edwards was an illustrator in the late 1800s.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection were transferred from the New York University Archives Photograph Collection (PHOTO 00001) in May 2024. The accession number associated with this collection is 2024.042.
According to former University Archivist Joseph Roberto, materials in this collection were discovered in 1985 inside the partitioning on the first floor of #80 Washington Square, where the concierge desk once stood.
Drawings; Correspondence.; Illustrations.; Costume.; Edwards, Harry Clay
- Sketches, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Xeroxes of Original Drawings (Not Complete), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence and Photographs, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Sketch of Man, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lyceum Dramatic Society, undated (Box 1, Folder 6, Box Shared University Archives 152, Folder 9)
- Engraving Proofs, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 7, Box Shared University Archives 152, Folder 10)
- Small Costume Sketches, Pencil, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Large Costume Sketches, Pencil, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sketches of Women in Dresses, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Sketches of Men, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Sketches of Women, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Pencil Drawing -- Man at Desk with Child at Left, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Published Illustrations by Other Artists Collected by Edwards, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Half Tone Proofs, 1890 (Box Shared University Archives 152, Folder 11)